<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <!-- Main menu -->
    <item name="LOADING"                  value="Loading..."/>

    <item name="MAIN_MENU"                value="Squares 3D"/>
    <item name="START_SINGLEPLAYER"       value="Start Game"/>
    <item name="RULES"                    value="Game Rules"/>
    <item name="CONTROLS"                 value="Controls"/>
    <item name="CREDITS"                  value="Credits"/>
    <item name="QUIT_GAME"                value="Quit Game"/>

    <item name="RLY_QUIT"                 value="Do you really want to quit?"/>

    <item name="BACK"                     value="Back"/>

    <!-- Singleplayer menu -->
    <item name="EASY"                     value="Easy Level"/>
    <item name="NORMAL"                   value="Normal Level"/>
    <item name="HARD"                     value="Hard Level"/>
    <item name="EXTRA"                    value="Extra Level"/>

    <item name="CREDITS_SCREEN">Programming &amp; Design:
Mārtiņš Možeiko
Kristaps Straupe

Also credits goes to:
Atis Straujums (extra level),
Gustavs Gūtmanis (logo &amp; icon)
Dmitry Chirkov (player model)
Martin Offermann (menu music &amp; sound effects)
Alexander Belov (Russian translation)
Dirk Stegemann (German translation)
Game music by trash80 (taken from trash80.net)
And other people who have helped us!</item>

    <item name="RULES_SCREEN">
    Game begins with a throw of the ball in the middle of the field. Players may not touch the ball before it has hit
the ground 3 times. Otherwise the player who has touched the ball earlier gets 1 minus point.
    With each touch of the player to the ball the count of potential minuses is increased by 1 point.
    Player recieves a minus point when:
        * Ball has left the field from the player`s field. Player then recieves as many minus points as there have been
          touches to the ball while it has been in air. If the player was the last one who had hit the ball before it left the
          field from the player`s square of field, he recieves as many minus points as he had gathered while ball was in
          the air after the last touch to the ball (if any) by any of opponents.
        * Ball has left the field from the body of the player. In this scenario the player recieves as many minus points
          as he had gathered while ball was in the air after the last touch to the ball (if any) by any of opponents.
    While the ball has not hit the ground outside of the field the player may try to catch it and get back into game
field while keeping it in air. While the ball has not hit the ground outside of the game field, the game continues.
Objects which are above ground are not counted as ground thus if the ball hits them, the game is not yet stopped.
    If player recieves the minus point, the game is resumed with a throw of the ball from that player`s field in diagonal
direction and it has to hit the same player`s field once and only after this event the diagonal player may touch the
ball while others have to wait for him to touch it or for the ball to hit his (diagonal) field before they can touch the ball.
If any of players fails to obey this rule he gets 1 minus point.
    If ball has left the game field from any of middle lines the game is resumed with a throw of the ball in the middle
of the game field. Players may touch the ball once it has hit the ground.
    The player who first recieves 21 points loses the game.
    </item>

    <item name="CONTROLS_SCREEN">
Ingame controls:
  * Touch screen and drag to rotate
  * Touch and drag &lt;M&gt; control to move your player
  * Press &lt;C&gt; button to catch ball
  * Press &lt;J&gt; button to jump
  * Press &lt;Pause&gt; button to pause game
</item>

    <!-- Ingame texts -->
    <item name="FPS_DISPLAY"           value="FPS: $1"/>
    <item name="PLAYER_KICKS_OUT_BALL" value="$1 kicks the ball out!&#10;+$2"/>
    <item name="OUT_FROM_FIELD"        value="Out from $1 field!&#10;+$2"/>
    <item name="OUT_FROM_MIDDLE_LINE"  value="Ball out from middle line!"/>
    <item name="PLAYER_TOUCHES_TWICE"  value="$1 touches twice!&#10;+$2"/>
    <item name="PLAYER_UNALLOWED"      value="$1 touched the ball preliminary!&#10;+$2"/>

    <item name="HITS_COMBO"            value="$1 Hits combo!!"/>
    <item name="HITS"                  value="$1 Hits!!"/>

    <item name="SCORE_MESSAGE"         value="$1: $2"/>

    <item name="ESC_MESSAGE">
Pause

Touch here to quit to Main Menu..
or somewhere else to resume game.
    </item>

    <item name="CONTINUE">
Congratulations, You have cleared this level!

Touch screen to return to Main Menu.
    </item>
    
    <item name="RESTART">
You`ve lost the game..

Touch here to quit to Main Menu..
or somewhere else to retry the game.
    </item>

    <item name="PAUSE"             value="Pause"/>

    <item name="FINISHED_GAME">
Congratulations, You have finished Extra level!
Now you are The Ultimate Master of Squares.
No one can defeat You anymore!
Touch screen to return to Main Menu.
    </item>

    <item name="GAME_OVER"             value="Game has ended!"/>

    <item name="TRUE"                     value="Yes"/>
    <item name="FALSE"                    value="No"/>
</xml>
